Lucy Abramyan

Software Engineer at Google

Summary

I'm a software engineer with a passion for numbers. I like to explore, build, challenge, and mentor. I worked with robots at JPL, and am working on Augmented Reality at Google.

I hate working on "low hanging fruit" problems.

I don't care which programming languages, operating systems, or platforms you're developing in. Are you doing cool things that are going to change the world?

Experience

Software Engineer at Google

September 2012 - Present

I work as a software engineer at Google to make augmented reality easy.

I used to develop health and fitness insights in Google Fit by crunching numbers with MapReduce and building end-to-end features on both Android and the web.

I used to work in Image Search.

Software Engineer at Jet Propulsion Laboratory

July 2008 - August 2012 (4 years 2 months)

I worked as a software engineer at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) to develop operations software for NASA missions and research robots. I investigated new technologies (both hardware and software) to enhance the user interface experience. This included multi-touch displays, large immersive displays, and various types of game controllers.

I was the lead engineer of our 270-degree cylindrical display. Our immersive display system addressed visualization problems during operations, for example correctly estimating the size and relative positions of objects from ATHLETE's environment. The display surrounded the viewer with panoramic imagery to provide situational awareness during operations.

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lcwziICVMKA

Software Engineer Intern at Jet Propulsion Lab - Cal Tech (NASA)

June 2003 - August 2007 (4 years 3 months)

Education

University of Southern California

Master's degree, Computer Science, 2009 - 2012

Harvey Mudd College

Computer Science, Computer Science, Economics, 2004 - 2008

Activities and Societies: Sigma Xi, Association for Computing Machinery (ACM), Society of Women

Engineers (SWE)

Clark Magnet High School

Lucy Abramyan

Software Engineer at Google



Contact Lucy on LinkedIn